A Guide to the Undergraduate English Honors Theses, 1979-1994
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
- "The Ephemeral Feminine: Keats, Contingency, and Self-Creation" by Virginia Heffernan 1991 (Box 22)
- "Moral Instructor or Social Critic: A Metacritical Examination of Jane Austen Before and After the Women's Movement" by Shari Lynn Little 1991 (Box 22)
- "The Problems of Reading In The Crying of Lot 49" by Chris Reeder 1991 (Box 22)
- "We have all of Us One Human Heart: Hardship and Courtship in the Social Problem Novels of Elizabeth Gaskell" by Catherine Roach 1991 (Box 22)
- "Tis but thy name that is thine enemy: Typee and Narrative Anonymity" by Spencer William Salas 1991 (Box 22)
- "H.D.'s Gift and the Creation of the Female Persona" by Mara Noelle Scanlon 1991 (Box 22)
- "Towards a Map of Paradise: Rhetoric of Myth and Precision in Ezra Pound's Pisan Cantos" by Brian Patrick Sullivan 1991 (Box 23)
- "Do we get to win this time? American War Films' Construction of Race and Gender" by Kimberly Marie Tso 1991 (Box 23)
- "Through the Window of the Grace: Identity and Death in Pedro Paramo and Aura" by Susan Marie Trabert 1991 (Box 23)
- "The Homo-erotics of Wilfred Owen's Poetry: Patriotism, Gender, and Poetic Tradition" by Nick Yasinski 1991 (Box 23)
- " Hamlet: The Internal Struggle in an External Reality" by Guy Trent Aulbaugh 1992 (Box 23)
- "The Heroic Code in Old English Literature: A Means of Recovering the Thought World of the Past" by Thomas Frederick Berger 1992 (Box 23)
- "The Ghost in the Machine: Artificial Intelligence in Literature and Film" by Shawn Michael E. Carnell 1992 (Box 23)
- "Herself Discovered: H.D.'s Poems Based on Fragments of Sappho" by Katherine Derderian 1992 (Box 23)
- "Perils and Paradox: A Study of Seamus Heaney's Conception of Poetry" by Greg Easley 1992 (Box 23)
- "Conflation, Construction and Skepticism: The Quest for Truth and The Feminine in John Keats" by Karen Elizabeth Gale 1992 (Box 23)
- "The Presence of the Past: Hawthorne as a Moral Historian" by Caroline Alexander Greene 1992 (Box 24)
- "The Artistic Daughter's Vision: Woolf's Daughters and Mothers in The Voyage Out, Night and Day, and To the Lighthouse" by Lauren T. Hoenig 1992 (Box 24)
- "A Dance in the Making: Poetry and Personal Poetics" by Ann L. Hudson 1992 (Box 24)
- "Chambered Pistil and Sword-Bearing Archangel: Amy Clampitt and Adrienne Rich on the Possibilities of Political Poetry" by Elizabeth Cain Inglesby 1992 (Box 24)
- " The Paris Review and American Expatriation in the 1850s' by Alan Robert Katz 1992 (Box 24)
- "The Body and The Spirit in Alignment: The Struggle Between the Body and the Spirit in Coriolanus and Anthony and Cleopatra" by Francis Whitney Kendrick 1992 (Box 24)
- "Chaucer's Make Believe: Sacramental Play and Playful Sacrament in The Canterbury Tales" by James Kozloski 1992 (Box 24)
- "A Glittering Guitar-Shaped Fish: Immediacy in the Short Stories of William Carlos Williams and Charles Bukowski" by John H. Longwell 1992 (Box 24)
- "A Summoning Together: The Transformation of Platonic Thought in To the Lighthouse" by Vivian Hunt Macpherson 1992 (Box 24)
- "Gertrude Stein: Towards a New Way of Knowing; The interplay of language and identity in her early works 'Melanctha,' Two and Tender Buttons" by Jean Katherine Martin 1992 (Box 24)
- "The legend of Good Women and the Fictions of Writing and Reading" by John Ramsburgh 1992 (Box 25)
- "Love That Cuts Like the Cold Wind: Parents and Children in the Fiction of Flannery O' Connor" by Margaret Keith Smythe 1992 (Box 25)
- "Gazing at the Text: Spectatorial Identification in Hitchcock's Vertigo and Rear Window" by Brad Summerhill 1992 (Box 25)
- "Loves Deep Anger: Intimacy and Female Power in Eudora Welty's Four Major Novels" by Elizabeth Moore Rhodes Warren 1992 (Box 25)
- "From the Word to the Resurrection: The Literary, Historical, and Theological Unity of the Gospel of John" by Yvonne M. Anderson 1993 (Box 25)
- "Balances of Image and Narrative: W.S. Merwin, Seamus Heaney, and Dave Smith and An Art To It: Poems" by John Thomas Casteen IV 1993 (Box 25)
- "At Best A Contradiction still: Alexander Pope's softer man and the Construction of Poetic Authority" by Dennis Foley Connolly 1993 (Box 25)
- "Don DeLillo and the American Reel: The Image and the Individual" by Christopher Paul Cordani 1993 (Box 25)
- "Is it a Boy or a Girl?: Homosexuality and the Privilege of Unknowing in The Great Gatsby" by Allen Clifford Durgin 1993 (Box 25)
- "Above Th'Aonian Mount' A critical Examination of Milton's Ambitious Aspirations and the Necessary Arguments which Deny and/or Defend that Ambition" by Frances Ellen Edinger 1993 (Box 25)
- "Rebuilding the House: The Reduction of Critical Distance and Destabilization of Narrative Structure within Charles Dickens's Bleak House and Our Mutual Friend" by Robin Neil Follet 1993 (Box 26)
- "Exalting the Present and the Real; Examining Continuities in Walt Whitman's Journalism and Poetry" by Lisa Gwendolyn Guernsey 1993 (Box 26)
- "Ah Done Growed Ten Feet Higher Jus From Listenin Tuh You An Exploration of Women's Shared Experiences of Narrative in Traditional Quilts, Zora Neale Hurston's Their Eyes Were Watching God and Faith Ringgold's Story Quilts" by Jennifer Lynn Hanna 1993 (Box 26)
- "Dreams of Passion: Theatrically in Henry IV, Part One, and Hamlet" by Andrew Heffernan 1993 (Box 26)
- "The Fantastic and the Marvelous; In Short Stories by Julio Cortezar: A search for a more Complete and Immanent Reality" by Toinette Carmen Lobo 1993 (Box 26)
- "A Way Without Words: Virginia Woolf's Search For Feminine Voice in The Years" by Julia Corinne Lock 1993 (Box 26)
- "Saving Grace: A Modern Screenplay Adaptation of Sir Gawain and the Green Knight With a Brief Critical Epilogue" by Bill L. Platt 1993 (Box 26)
- "George Eliot as Marian Evans: The Endorsement of the Feminine Standard of Culture" by Elizabeth Joan Reed 1993 (Box 26)
- "Tragic Perceptions of Female Sexuality in Hamlet and Othello" by Julie Rutherford 1993 (Box 26)
- "The Truth Is In the Telling: A Comparative Study of Jack Tales Among African American and White Communities" by Sharon Lynne Smith 1993 (Box 27)
- "A Feminist Interrogation of Freudian and Lacanian Psychoanalytic Theory; The Superego, The Symbolic and the Implications of Phallocentrism" by Jeanie D. Cassar 1993 (Box 27)
- "The Fruits of Buried Feelings: The Suppression of Passion and the Growth of Interior Spaces in George Sand and Charlotte Bronte" by Jennifer Greiman 1994 (Box 27)
- "Demonic Exclusivity in the War Poetry of Walt Whitman and Winifred Owen" by Michael Griffin 1994 (Box 27)
- "Reading and the Rose: Studies in Medieval and Modern Analytical Modes" by Jennifer Lee Jonak 1994 (Box 27)
- "Legacy: A story of Youth and Inheritance" by Robert Fleming Puckett 1994 (Box 27)
- "Malady of Genius: The Problem of Education for Mary Wollstonecraft and Mary Shelley" by Erik Simpson 1994 (Box 27)
- "I Will Tell You-But Where, Where, Where? Locating Female Freedom: Edith Wharton's Dialogue Between America and Europe" by Kelly Marie Taylor 1994 (Box 27)
- "Dost Thou Speak Like A King? The performance of Kingship in Shakespeare's Henriad" by Charles Tucker Waldruff 1994 (Box 27)
- "Creation, Inspiration, and conflict: Degrees of Femininity in William Carlos Williams's Paterson" by Kimberly Alicia Weeks 1994 (Box 27)
- "Western Realism and Asian-American Immigrant Writing: Two Trends in the Contemporary American Short Story" by Edward Wong 1994 (Box 27)